welcome back everyone
and today we are going to start with the most valuable lesson we will ever be taught in GTNH
rely on the old way of doing things
just because you unlocked a new way of doing things a little bit more efficiently
it doesn't mean you have to start using it right away
indeed, in the last episode we figured out we can get three times the amount of plates out of the same ores by using those steam machines
the issue is that while we get a way better yield by using those machines
those machines are also incredibly slow
so, we are going to ignore those machines and go back to the good old vanilla furnaces
which we are powering with the creosote oil leftover from the Coke Ovens which we have to use somehow
using the hammer, we are getting so many resources anyways that that's a sufficient way of processing ores it's not a big deal
and with that, we have so many ingots that we can just smash those with a hammer
and stock up iron plates just like that
and while we could work on the main objective of this age just like that
we are not going to use those iron plates for that main objective
what we are using those plates for is to upgrade our single block workshop into a multi block workshop
we are crafting so much stuff that even NEI auto crafting is too slow
and after crafting a bunch of parts
we can start actually building something
so, the first thing we will have is a steam tank
this will act as a buffer for the steam we produce
i know it sounds weird, storing steam in a tank, it should like condense and fall down as water
but don't think too much about it
this time I'm going to leave it on the roof of my house
because I'm going to do solar boilers, my favorite way of making energy
but right now that's going to be it
then I already prepared two big of burning boxes
I think I'm going to use it like that at the beginning
but soon enough, I will turn these into bigger size
and also one block taller
but for the moment, just this one
OK, the bigger you make this tank
the more it takes to heat up
I want a bigger tank too
but I'm going to get Steam Press before finishing the rest
then to make water
the power of this one probably it's enough to use that water tank
but I want to make right away the better water pump
this one can handle way more machines
here we go
we pipe it up so it can actually get some steam to work
OK, the downside of this water pump is that it takes some steam to work
it makes way more water than using the other tanks
but it does require a little bit of power in the form of steam
and then we need some water here to kick start this one
there you go
and we can start heating it up
once again, has to reach one hundred degrees before it makes any steam
as far as I remember, this one, the hotter it is the more it makes steam
there are other boilers
but I like this one
and we must not forget to pipe the water
to the boiler
and here I also have a handy water pipe for the future
usually I heavily suggest clicking all of the pipe to make it flow nicer
OK, once the steam reaches half
it will start pushing into the tank
this tank has some valves
this tank is made out of three blocks
there is the main structure block, glass which is like the cheaper
and there are those valves that allow you to input/output
the output is only from the bottom
no, I mean the tank automatically outputs from the bottom
so you can attach a pipe on the bottom of this one, and the tank will push steam into that pipe
but it does not do that on the sides or on the top
so as I were saying on the bottom soon enough we would have some steam
and then we can run this steam to the machines
want to keep some of the old machines too
but I'm going to build multiblocks too
I mean we already have those machines
so may as well keep those for a few times we need to craft a little bit of things
those bigger multiblocks work in batches
but those multiblocks are also quite expensive to build
so we may as well start saving some materials by using these small multi blocks
which we can now power a little bit easier with the new boiler
at this point of the game
we probably also want to have a little bit of automation
so, with those machine, the automation consists of just using hopper
so hopper in stuff, hopper out into chests, the output
and with that, we can now more easily craft some more expensive machines that would work way better
the first one I want to do is the steam grinder
that is because the single block macerater is basically impossible to use
it's just too slow
while the forge hammer and alloy smelter are decent I will say for the moment
so, you prepare all of the blocks required
just prepare everything
then you can manually build it
or you can just craft one of those multiblock structure hologram projector
and then you click on the thing and it builds for you
so my suggestion is first figure out where you want the hatches
and then once you decided where to put the hatches build the machine
by the way, the amount of those you use when you try to build the machine will change the tier of the machine
so if you click with a single spell
it will do a level one machine
if you click with a stack of two
it will try to make a tier two
for instance with this multiblock tier one means bronze, tier two means steel
the next thing we have to worry about is the pipe to hook it up
now to figure out which pipe to use is not too easy
right now you probably can only use bronze pipes
and each pipe has a different capacity
now if you look at the controller usage you can get an idea of how much steam it could take
the issue is that some recipe use way more steam than then the others
so figuring out what pipe to use can be tricky
for the moment, I'm just going to use some normal pipes
and in the future I will decide what pipe to use
and by the way, by now I can also upgrade the tank
and I have already upgraded the boiler because the small one was not keeping up even with the single box
and there we have our bigger tank with two thousand buckets of capacity
another thing you may want to pay attention to is that this one is quite efficient
the steam usage you see here is not the one you should be looking at when you look at the multiblock
because this multiblock has a speed buff, a steam usage discount
but most importantly some parallels
so if you look for example at the
random iron ore
all of the ores should have the same amount of steam used
which is supposed to be eighty liters per second
but as you can see here
it's actually using four hundred
that's because it has a eight parallel
if you do eighty times eighty
enter
you can also use a calculator just by opening the chat and typing equals space and then the calculation you want to do
so you can see it's supposed to be say six hundred forty
but we have to account also for the discount which is sixty two
uh, so we have sixty two five
and now you get four hundred
that zero zero zero zero six is the float
so you can see the math, math out
so if we use this one only to crush ores
a four hundred (L/sec) pipe, which is half of a small bronze pipe will be enough
but of course we are going to power other machines
and someday we will probably macerate something that will take more steam than this pipe can carry
but for the moment, I think it's better to chip out a little bit on pipes
and later on when it's an issue
craft some bigger pipes and repurpose the old pipes
and you also have to be careful about that
because unlike single block
if a multi block runs out of steam
it won't simply restart the process
but it will power fail and void whatever it was processing
so, you actually do lose items if those multiblocks run out of steam
but that's the mechanism you're going to have to deal multiple times with
if that happens and you want to be a little bit more careful
one way is to open the control panel and reduce the parallel
because parallel is what causes the cost to really increase
so if you lower the parallel, you will also lower the energy consumption
but of course the best solution is to use bigger pipes
and to increase your power production
here I have two boilers now
and now that our workshop is really well set
we can finally start working on the Brick Blast Furnace
now this is quite expensive
so you probably want a few tips on how to deal with this
I mean the first tip was to get all of the steam multiblocks
but let's see how to use those at the best way possible
and the main thing is that it looks
like you need a lot of clay
but you don't actually need any clay
clay is required for two things
one is bricks and one is clay dust for the concrete
but instead of collecting clay in normal way
it's way better to collect terracotta and then macerate it
terracotta for the clay dust
and bricks from a dungeon for the brick dust
if you are lucky but not even too much lucky
you can find
can find a Canyon biome which basically has more mountains made out of Terracotta
that biome looks orange and reddish
it's not too hard to find
but I didn't explore much this playthrough
so I didn't find any
you can also find some on mountain biome
which has still a lot of that stuff
so just collect it and then macerate it
for the bricks just look for a brick dungeon
you can take all of the bricks on the house above
but once you collect all of those
there is still a lot of bricks
did they have this one too
OK, and there are still a lot of bricks under this dungeon
have been told that there are like there are 1000 and even more blocks
it depends on where it spawns
depending on the absolute height it spawns
it can be deeper and thus have more bricks
this is a relatively easy to find dungeon usually
so it shouldn't be hard to find
I already found two of those in this playthrough
but usually you can find a lot of those dungeons
it's not hard to find
look around a lot
you can find good stuff in those dungeons too
to macerate one of those bricks, it takes one second to get one dust
to macerate the brick, it takes twenty times as much to get one quarter
and then you just use the good machines to stock up your inventory with the main parts of the Brick Blast Furnaces
then my suggestion is to fill up your inventory with water buckets and just craft the thing
now, it used to be life-saving using the forestry worktable
because that will save your recipe and craft nicely
but nowadays we got NEI auto-crafting
and then you just start spam crafting as many bricks as you can
now, as you can see I'm crafting way more bricks than the quest book asks for
and that's because of course, one brick blast furnace will be basically useless
you will want, I would say, a minimum of four Brick Blast Furnaces
that's the minimum I will get
then usually work towards twelve or even sixteen Brick Blast Furnaces
but there are many things you can do in this modpack
so while you wait for this
this is an awfully slow process
it takes six minutes per each ingot of steel per each furnace
so with four Brick Blast Furnaces, you don't get even one steel ingot per minute
you get less
you need six Brick Blast Furnaces just to get one ingot of steel per minute
and you will want a lot of steel
so get a lot of Brick Blast Furnaces
by the way we build those Brick Blast Furnaces all of the way back there because those make a lot of pollution
you can disable pollution in configuration
but I like to keep it enabled as it is by default
so build those a little bit far from your main house if you don't want the pollution to make a disaster
and while the steel is being produced
you can work on other things
for example you can work on crops
which I'm probably going to do in a livestream between episodes
or you can worry about the fuel
talking of which, it is also an issue for our current steam production
right now
I'm burning planks because I can easily chop down the huge rainforest trees that have a lot of logs inside
and then I can simply double the amount of fuel value by crafting those into planks
uh, by the way, to get these rainforest Oak which is a really nice to farm
you can just craft this sapling with a super easy recipe
and it makes a lot of wood
remember to repair your axes between things
but the thing I actually want to use is Coke Ovens
OK, getting those now is way easier
because you can use this recipe
and you can work with these big machines to get more Coke Ovens
and you can also automate those now
while our Brick Blast Furnaces is slowly working
we can start preparing more Coke Ovens
and this time we're going to try to automate those nicely
so, after crafting all of the blocks for the Coke Ovens and the new Coke Oven hatches that will allow to automate those
never used those
so I'm going to craft a bunch
and so we can wall share a lot of Coke Ovens
and then set those new hatches to do the function we want
and once we figure out how we want to layout the pipes
we connect up everything
you have to be careful with item pipes because most likely you only want to use a tin item pipes
and those cannot be removed using an iron wrench
you need an extra steel wrench to be able to remove those
so be careful if you place this
the other issue is that two input ingredients
most likely if you try to use a hopper
which you totally can do
it's going to be slow, I think
because the hopper can only push items one at a time
and the item pipe can only take items every four seconds
it could take a full stack
but the hopper only pushes one
so it gets one item every four seconds
and that's rather slow
it may be good enough for the moment
but if you want
you can just craft a conveyor belt
which is a little bit expensive but I'll tell you what,
it doesn't even take any steel
and then you add it to the pipe
shift click, import, to make it work properly
and this one will pull one full stack at a time working, way better
No, it's sixteen
but it works sixteen times better than before
by the way, if you mis-click and place a plate on a pipe
you can recover it using a crowbar
this mechanic can be quite handy for example with the steam pipes that will hurt you if you get too close
so you can put for example stone plates which is probably the cheapest plate you can make
or I mean if you want you can use any metal
that way you can walk on it nicely
also pipes sometimes bug out a little bit like
not exactly a flat thing when you walk walk over it
so maybe sometimes it glitch out
so maybe you want to put a plate on it
so you can walk really nicely on pipes if you do that
anyways, now we can go back to our currently manual farm
in the future we will automate this
but for the moment it's relatively easy to just chop down those huge trees like that
drop the wood into drawer
and it will slowly make charcoal that we can use on our Brick Blast Furnaces
those coke ovens will also produce creosote oil as we saw at the beginning of the series
and we can use that creosote oil into a fluid burning boiler
which will turn all of that creosote oil into steam
and now we can just build more Brick Blast Furnaces and maybe work on our crops
as soon as we will have enough steel
we can just move on to the next age
which is LV
basically all we need to move on to the next tier is just a little bit of steel
but I think this stuff are really counts as electricity
so this is going to be for the next episode
and with that, I think I'm going to close here
see you next time
bye bye
欢迎回来，各位
今天我们将从GTNH教给我们的最有价值的一课开始：
沿用老方法
当你解锁了一种新的看起来效率稍高的做事方式时
这并不意味着你必须立刻开始使用它
确实，在上一集里，我们发现用这些蒸汽机器，同样数量的矿石可以产出三倍数量的板
可问题是，虽然这样能省不少材料
但这些机器非常非常慢
所以，我们将忽略这些机器，沿用老方法：原版熔炉
我们用焦炉剩下来的杂酚油为其供能，反正这些杂酚油我们也得想办法用掉
用锻造锤的话，反正我们能获得大量资源，处理矿石的方式效率低点也无所谓了
这样一来，锭的数量多到直接用锤子砸板也不用担心不够用
就这样，囤点铁板
接下来我们可以继续跟着任务书的主线任务走
但这次，我们不会把这些铁板用来完成这个主线任务
我们要用这些铁板把我们的单方块机器工作间升级成多方块机器工作间
我们需要合成的东西多到即使用 NEI 自动合成也感觉很慢
在制作了一堆零件之后
我们终于可以开始建造了
我们第一个要做的是个蒸汽储罐（译注：RC蓄水器）
作为我们生产的蒸汽的缓存
我知道这听起来很怪，把蒸汽存储罐里，照常理它应该会在罐子里液化成水聚在底部
但这是游戏，不要想太多
嗯，这次我要在自家屋顶上建造
因为我要做太阳能锅炉，这是我最喜欢的产能方式
但目前就先这样
我已经准备了两格大的燃烧室
在发展前期我大概会就先这样用着
但以后我会把它改成更大的尺寸
同时再加一格高度
但目前，就先这样
OK，这个锅炉你造得越大
加热所需的时间就越长
我还想要一个更大的蒸气储罐
但在做那些事情之前我得先做出大型蒸汽锻造锤
至于供水
这个的耗水量可能用那个集水器就够了
但我想直接做更好的蒸气水泵
这个可以支撑起大量机器的消耗
好了
我们用管道把它连起来，这样它就能输入蒸汽工作了
OK，这个水泵的缺点是工作需要消耗一些蒸汽
它比RC集水器产的水多得多
但它需要消耗一点蒸汽形式的能量
然后我们需要在这里加点水来发动它
好了
现在就可以开始预热了
再说一次，必须达到100度才会产生蒸汽
我没记错的话，这东西温度越高产生的蒸汽就越多。
呃，整合包里还有其他类型的锅炉可以用
但我比较喜欢这个
以及我们一定不能忘了接管道把水
送入锅炉
这里我还预留了一根方便以后使用的输水管道
我强烈建议把管道都用扳手右键shift点一下（限制流动方向），这样流体能流动得更顺畅
OK，蒸汽存量超过一半后
它就会开始把蒸气推出到储罐
这个储罐有几个阀门
具体一点，这个储罐由三种方块组成
有主结构方块，相对便宜好造一点的玻璃
以及这些可以让你输入/输出流体的阀门
它只会从底部输出
呃，我是指RC储罐会从底部自动推出内容物
所以你可以在它的底部接个管道，这样储罐自动会把蒸汽推出到管道里
但侧面或顶面都不会这样自动推出
所以如前面所说，底部，很快就会有蒸汽了
我们接下来就可以把蒸汽一路传到机器里了
我打算保留一些旧机器
但我也要建多方块机器
我是说我们已经有那些旧机器了
所以不妨留着它们，偶尔我们需要合成点小东西的时候用
那些更大的多方块机器能够进行批量加工处理
相应的，建造成本也高很多
所以我们不妨先用这些小型多方块来省一些材料
毕竟我们现在也可以用新锅炉更轻松地给这些机器供能了
玩到了这个阶段的时候
我们可能就想做一点自动化了
对于这些机器，自动化只需要用漏斗
——用漏斗塞进原料，再用漏斗把产物转移到箱子里
这样，我们就能更轻松地合成一些更贵但很强的机器
我想做的第一个是大型蒸汽研磨机
因为单方块研磨机基本上没法用
它慢的跟蜗牛一样
而锻造锤和合金炉的速度……还彳亍吧 对于现在来说
所以，接下来准备好所有需要的方块
准备好一切之后
你可以手动建造它的多方块结构
或者你也可以合成一个多方块机器全息投影仪
用它对着机器右键一下，它就自动帮你建好了
所以我的建议是先确定你想把仓室放在哪里
确定好仓室的位置后，再建造机器
顺便说一下，建造机器时全息投影仪的物品堆叠数量会改变将要建造的机器的等级
所以如果你用单个物品右键
它就会建造一级机器
如果你用两个堆叠在一块右键
它就会尝试建造二级的
比如这个多方块，一级是青铜的，二级是钢的
而接下来需要考虑的是怎么给它接上管道
对于现在，弄清楚该用哪种管道不太容易
现在你可能只能用青铜管道
每个管道都有不同的容量
你可以用NEI查看多方块控制器的用途，以此大致了解它可能需要多少蒸汽
主要的问题在于有些配方的蒸气消耗速率比其他配方高得多
所以弄清楚该用那种管道可能会有点麻烦
现在我就只用一些普通的管道
将来我会再决定是否使用以及使用什么管道
顺便说一下，现在我也可以升级储罐了
我也已经升级成了大号锅炉，因为小号的RC锅炉甚至不如之前做的小型燃煤锅炉
我们还有了更大的储罐，容量足足有2000桶
另一个值得注意的事情是这东西相当高效
你在这里看到的蒸汽用量，并不是你用多方块机器时的实际用量
因为这个多方块有速度加成，还有蒸汽消耗折扣
以及最重要的，有并行
因此，如果你查看例如
随便一个铁矿石
所有的矿石应该都消耗同量蒸汽
应该，都是每秒80L/s
但正如这里显示的
它的实际消耗是400L/s
因为它有8并行
你可以算一下：80乘以80
回车
对了，你可以用游戏内置的计算器：打开聊天，输入一个等于号，一个空格，然后输入要进行的计算
你可以看到这里计算出结果应该是640
但我们还得乘上折扣，也就是62…
呃，是62.5%
最终结果是400
那个.00000000000000006是浮点数…（译注：浮点数精度误差）
不论如何，我们一步一步算出来了结果
所以如果我们只用这个来粉碎矿石
一个400L/s的管道...也就是半个小型青铜流体管道的量就足够了
当然，我们还需要为其他机器提供能量
并且我们以后总有可能会研磨一些蒸气消耗速率超出这根管道的流体容量的东西
但目前我觉得还是在管道上省一点比较好
等以后有问题的时候
再做更大的管道，把这些旧的换下来用在别的地方
以及你还需要注意
和单方块不同
如果多方块机器耗尽蒸汽
它不会简单地重置加工进度
而是会“跳电”(跳蒸气？)并直接销毁耗尽时正在处理的物品
所以，如果这些多方块机器耗尽了蒸汽，你会实实在在的丢失物品
这会是你需要应对很多次的机制
如果发生这种情况，以及你想谨慎一点
一种处理方法是打开控制面板，降低并行数
因为并行才是消耗速率真正增加的原因
所以如果你降低并行数，也会降低消耗速率
当然，最好的解决方案还是换成更大的管道
同时加强你的能源产出
就比如现在我加到了两个锅炉同时工作
现在我们的工作间布置好了
我们终于可以开始建造砖高炉了
这玩意挺贵的
所以你可能需要一些小技巧/小建议
第一个建议是先把所有蒸汽多方块机器做出来
接下来让我们看看如何以最好的方式使用它们
一个值得注意的地方是尽管任务看起来
像是你需要准备很多黏土的样子
但实际上你根本不需要黏土
这里黏土就只用来做两个东西
一个是砖块，另一个是混凝土用的黏土粉
但与其用常规方式收集黏土
你可以直接挖陶瓦，然后把它丢进研磨机
研磨陶瓦可以直接获得黏土粉
相应的挖地牢里的砖块研磨来获得砖粉
如果你运气不错（不需要非常欧）
你应该能找到
能找到一个峡谷（译注：实际上是恶地Badlands）生物群系，那里有不少由陶瓦构成的山脉
那个生物群系看起来是橙红色的
其实不是很难找
但这次通关流程中我没怎么花时间探索
所以我没有找到陶瓦山
不过你也可以在山地生物群系中找到一些
那里也有不少货
所以，收集起来然后研磨就行
至于砖块，只需寻找砖块地牢
你可以直接挖掉整个房子的砖块
如果还不够的话
地下部分也有不少砖块（译注：所以被不少人戏称为“砖矿脉”）
（这个是不是没生成地下部分？）
哦，没毛病，这地牢的地下部分也有不少砖块
听说有一千多个砖块
这取决于它生成在哪里
也就是生成位置的绝对高度
它可以更深，有更多的砖
这是个相对好找的地牢
应该不难找
我在这次通关流程中已经找到两个了
你应该也能找到很多这样的地牢
找起来应该不难
多跑图，多转转
你也可以在地牢里找到其他的好东西
研磨一整个砖块，需要消耗一秒钟(20tick)得到一份砖粉
而研磨单个砖头则需要二十倍的时间才能得到1/4粉
然后你只要用这些好用的机器批量合成，把砖高炉的主要部件塞满你的物品栏
然后我的建议是再多塞点水桶，直接开合
在旧版本，林业工作台可以说是救命稻草
因为它能保存配方预设自动摆放，很方便的进行批量合成
但如今我们有 NEI 自动合成了
我们就可以直接开始疯狂合成尽可能多的耐火砖
如你所见我做的砖头比任务书要求的多得多
这当然是因为，一个砖高炉基本上是没用的
我认为，你会需要至少四个砖高炉
这是我会做的最低数量
然后通常会朝着十二个甚至十六个砖高炉的方向努力
不过，在这个整合包中还有很多其他的可以做的事情
所以在你等这个的时候……
这个砖高炉烧制慢的要死
每个砖高炉每六分钟才能产出一个钢锭
所以用四个砖高炉，平均下来你每分钟连一个钢锭都产不出
产量就那么一点
你需要六个砖高炉才能平均每分钟产出一个钢钢锭
同时，以后你会需要很多很多钢
所以，多做点砖高炉吧
顺带一提，我们在后面那么远的地方建那些砖高炉是因为它们会产生很多污染
你可以在配置中禁用污染
但我喜欢保持整合包默认的启用状态
所以如果你不想体验污染带来的灾难，就把它们建在离你主基地稍远一点的地方。
在等烧钢的同时
在这个整合包中还有很多其他的可以做的事情
比如你可以弄弄作物杂交
我大概会在几集之间的直播里做这件事
或者你可以考虑考虑燃料来源
说起来这也是我们现在蒸汽生产的一个问题
现在
我在烧木板，因为砍掉有很多原木的巨大雨林橡树对我来说很轻松
而原木做成木板就可以让热值（燃烧时间）翻倍
呃，顺便说一下，这种非常值得专门种植的雨林橡树
它的树苗有一个超级简单的合成配方
这玩意产量惊人
砍完一棵之后别忘了修好你的斧头
我接下来想做的是焦炉
OK，现在做这东西比之前容易多了
因为现在你可以用这个配方了
你可以用这些大机器制作更多的焦炉
这些大机器现在我们也可以自动化了
所以，在等砖高炉组烧钢的时候
我们可以开始准备多做点焦炉
这次我们要尝试把这些自动化搞好
所以，在合成好焦炉所需的所有方块，以及新添加的能实现自动化的焦炉仓之后
我之前从没用过这些新添加的东西
所以我要多做点
这样我们就能让很多焦炉共用方块
然后把这些新仓设置成我们想要的功能
在我们排好管路之后
把一切都接起来
处理物品管道时有个事情需要注意一下，因为很可能你只会想用锡物品管道
而这些管道不能用铁扳手拆除
您需要一个额外的钢扳手才能拆掉它们
所以如果你放这个要注意一下这个问题
呃，另一个问题是需要输入两种不同的原料
你可能第一反应会是用原版漏斗
确实可以用它
但我觉得，它太慢了
因为漏斗一次只能推出一个物品
同时物品管道只能每四秒输入一次物品。
——物品管道其实每次都能接收一整组物品作为输入
但是漏斗只一次只输出一个
所以，最后结果是每四秒才进一个物品
这真的很慢
现在可能还算够用
但如果你想的话
你可以合成一个传送带
它会稍微贵一点，但
这东西不需要钢就能做
然后你可以把它安装到管道上
Shift+点击，输入模式，这样它才能正常工作
这个一次能拉入一整组，效果好得多
不对，是一次十六个（译注：tooltip里写了LV16个一组 每5s工作一次……）
反正效果比以前好了16倍
顺带的，如果你手滑不小心把板安装到了管道上
你可以用撬棍把它取回来
不过这个机制还有个很不错的特性：比如对于靠太近会烫伤你的蒸汽管道
你可以给它装上石板一类（石板大概是你能做的板里最便宜的了）
呃，其实你可以用任意金属板（译注：实际上任意覆盖板都行，包括木头板，纸，金属箔，透镜）
这样你就可以在上面随意行走，它不会再因为里面的极端温度流体而烫伤/冻伤你了
管道本身的碰撞体积还有点bug
当你在上面行走的时候 它会处于一个像是平地同时还像是楼梯的叠加态
就很容易像刚才这样出bug卡人
所以也许你可能还是会想在上面放块板的
毕竟这样在上面行走的时候就和普通的完整方块/平地一样，不会卡bug了
不管怎样，现在我们可以把目光挪回到我们的目前还是人力的树场了
未来我们会实现树场自动化
但就目前而言，像这样砍倒那些巨树还是相对容易的
把原木扔进抽屉
它就会慢慢产出木炭，可以用在砖高炉组上
这些焦炉也会产生杂酚油，就像我们在前面几期里看到过的那样
我们可以将杂酚油用于液态燃料锅炉
它会把所有的杂酚油变成蒸汽
接下来的时间里我们可以建造更多的砖高炉，也可以弄弄作物杂交
等到我们有足够的钢铁时
我们可以进入下一个章节
也就是 LV，低压
实际上，进下一阶只需要准备一点钢就可以了
但我觉得这东西是电而不是蒸气了
所以这将是下一集的内容
那么，我想这期就到这里了
下次见
拜拜